[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trien tasa Advanced Training as you all
know I already published 67 YouTube
videos covering beginers level
intermediate level and advanced level
Concepts from couple of videos onwards
I've started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases by using
trien tasa please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell iccon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank
you this is our lesson 68 in terms of
overall tric taskar training and this is
our obstacle 26 in terms of realtime
scenarios in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can we solve an obstacle
by interacting with the dynamic table
and the dynamic table contains the
embedded controls like text fields and
the drop down list so how can you
interact with the drop- down list and
how can you select the value from the
drop- down list by using the text
control which is in another cell of of
your web table so now let us go and see
in detail what is the obstacle that we
are going to solve for this is our
obstacle list and our obstacle name is
drop- down table which is categorized as
medium but as far as I know this is
almost like we can consider it as hard
let us go for
it and if you see here it says click
generate button I'm clicking on this
clicking on this generate button and
select write values and submit note that
the drop down contains only one element
matching the
criteria matching the criteria so first
drop down what is the criteria select
word that starts with letter X simply go
here this one X scan select word that
starts with letter r
recover select word that starts with
b b
I select word that starts with
w that starts with
o obstacle course select word that
starts with w web driver now simply
submit this see your automation problem
is solved successfully so what are we
doing here I need to Simply click click
generate button and I need to select the
drop- down values based on the task that
is specified here first of all if you
see this is your table this is your web
table and this is your first column and
this is your second column First Column
has the task which talks about what
drop- down value to be selected based on
these letters you need to select the
drop down value so this drop down is
under second column which is value
column right you need to select the
drop- down value based on this letter b
c and these letters are keep on changing
the selection of these drop down values
keeps changing based on the letters and
these letters are totally dynamic in
nature so how can we solve this
particular
problem let us go to trient TSA so
before we scan I would like to make sure
that I click on generate so that I can
capture all the objects generate button
the web table and submit button right so
now let us right click on this obstacles
scan
application and this is the application
that I would like to scan select this
application click on
scan so total three objects that I need
to C capture so if you see here this is
my generate button select this one which
is uniquely
identified and then you also need to
select submit
button which is also uniquely identified
and you need to select this table combo
box table select this and I would like
to also select one of this drop- down
button sorry one of this drop down I
need not to select all the drop downs
for this particular table but I can
select only one drop down which is
Select right but when
I select this dropdown it says the
selected item is not
unique however I would like to keep as
is because I'm going to solve the
problem while automating the test case
dynamically even though this
select drop down is not uniquely
identified I'm going to make this as
uniquely identified while automating our
test case how I'm going to let you know
okay so I just captured generate button
one entire table submit button and
within this particular table I also
captured one of the drop- down value
okay and now you can name this
particular module with the name of
obstacle
copy and provide the name with name of
obstacle save the
module and then close the
module and let me simply select try
again so that we can run the test case
from the beginning okay let's go back to
presenta so make sure that the module is
reflecting
here so what is our module our module is
this one the last module double click on
this and make sure all objects are
reflecting generate button submit button
and your web table so before I start
automating the test case I have to make
one small modification for select drop
down because my select drop down is not
uniquely identified correct why because
see this particular drop downs are
available within the table in one of the
cell so this table has my first row this
is one cell and this is my second C
second row this is my one cell and this
is my second cell that means the select
is that means the drop down is in inside
the table row cell so that's why what
I'm going to
do this select button right expand this
one I'm going to move this select drop
down inside the
cell now your select drop down is going
to uniquely identified because
if we specify the row number as two then
it consider this one if you specify the
row number as three then it consider
this drop down so that means I moved the
drop down into the cell so that this
drop down is uniquely
identified okay hope you all understand
so now let us start working on our test
case folder which is blue section in the
left
side so what I'm going to do here right
click on this test case folder
and create test
case name this as the obstacle name that
we copied earlier and then double click
on this
obstacle double click on this test
case and then to automate the test case
what I'm going to do I'm going to Simply
drag this module onto test
case now let expand this one let's
expand this one so here
first what is
our action you need to click on generate
button so that means here I can simply
enter click
operation once you click on generate
button then of course you'll be
selecting all the drop down values but
you also need to click on this submit
button right submit button and now how
can I I select the drop- down values
corresponding to the letters that are
specified in the First Column how can we
achieve that now if You observe closely
your drop down values are starting from
the second row of the table first row is
column header and this is my second row
so here go
here here under row I'm going to specify
this as
hash2 that means I'm instructing tosar
to select the second row so once I
select the second row what is my
cell my cell is first I need to identify
the
letter under First Column correct I need
to identify the letter what is the
letter based on that I need to select
the value in this case s is my letter
and this is my drop down value but how
can I get the value of this
letter so this particular text is in
column 1 that means cell one row two so
this is my row two and here I'm going to
specify as hash one which is my first
cell so here under first cell I'm going
to perform action mode verify and I'm
going to use XB exclude
buffer method here to store the value of
this letter end of the letters right how
can I do that I can simply copy this
until here copy
this and here I'm instructing task to
verify the first cell of second
row and while verifying this
entire this entire text verify until
here and then store here after colon I
specified the space because this has a
space here right space I'm calling X
buffer XB open curly Braes
XB here I'm going to specify the buffer
name here I'm going to say
letter and close curly braces so what it
does it is going to verify this entire
text is matching up or
not and it is going to exclude the
verification of this letter because this
letter is dynamic in
nature I cannot verify this I'm
instructing Tas because this is keep on
changing exclude that and once you
exclude once you exclude store this
letter into your buffer what is the
buffer name letter is the buffer name
that's why I'm specifying the action
mode as verify done that means now I'm
able to store the letter here here once
I store the letter now I need to select
the drop down where is the drop down my
drop down is in second cell of second
row right that means here this is my
second row come to first row perform
verification and then go to Second cell
this is my first
s # two and for second cell here I don't
want to verify this second cell I'm
going to select
this select this second cell and under
this second cell I would like to select
the value based on the letter that is
stored here I'm going to call here under
select I'm going to call the buffer
which I stored here open curly braces
capital B
open Square Braes close Square Braes and
then close curly Braes right this is my
syntax
here within the square braces I'm going
to call the same
buffer name that I stored here I'm
storing the last letter
here see here I'm calling the buffer but
my drop down value is not simply s here
right but it has s and then something
else that's why I'm going to use the
regular
expression in this case first it
stores S
letter and I would like to select the
drop down starts with yes that's why I'm
going to use regular expression
hasri so when I run this first it stores
the value of s and then it selects the
drop down that starts with yes and then
anything after yes right let me simply
run this particular test case first I'm
going to remove click here right I'm
going to Simply run this particular test
case right click and run I want to see
if it works or
not clicked on
generate and then if you see here it is
selected it has a c value and it
selected C so now we need to repeat this
for all drop down values how can we do
that very it is very simple it's very
simple what what I'm going to do I'm
going to Simply copy this
entire this one this entire step copy
this entire
step and paste this
here but this time what I'm going to do
here this all remains same this is my
third row right
this one third row first second third
and rest all remains same rest of the
logic go to first cell store the last
letter into your buffer and then
select the drop down value with the
letter that stored in buffer that's it
so let's I would like to repeat this for
three more times so this is two drop
down values and you have three more drop
down values so what I'm going to do
collapse this copy
this again paste here
2 3 I pasted three times and now simply
you're going to change the row as
[Music]
four
5 and then
six and then you'll be clicking on
submit right let's expand this second
row third row fourth row fifth row so
what we did here and let me simply
repeat this what I'm instructing first
I'm instructing tasar go to second
row and this is my first cell under
first cell you have to store the last
letter of this particular sentence into
your buffer and then go to your second
cell of second row this is my second
cell and I'm selecting this second cell
of second row and then select the drop
down that starts with the letter which
is stored in the
buffer I'm how I'm storing the letter
into a buffer by using XB exclude
buffer right so then I'm repeating the
same for
third row fourth row fifth row sixth row
and now you can simply change the state
of your work state now simply you can
change the work state to completed save
the test
case come
here just make click on try
again okay now let us run this
particular test case and see how it
works right click and run in scratchbook
it clicked on generate and then it
selected all the drop- down
values correctly you solve this
automation problem let me see here see
here
now this letter ends with t selected
tasar ends with v selected VN now B
distributed execution w web driver a
accelerator so these letters keeps on
changing the drop down Val and drop down
values also keeps on
changing so you need not to worry what
drop down value here right hope you all
understand the concepts it is bit
complex but once you understand the
method it's very easy so if you have any
queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries thank you hope you all
understand how can we solve an obstacle
where you need to interact with the
dynamic table and that Dynamic table
contains the embedded controls like text
field and the drop down list and you
need to select the value from the drop
down list by using the text field that
contains in another cell please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos and don't
forget to like and share the video thank
you
[Music]